The universe in its vastness,
is forever changing.
The Zu mountain ranges in Szuchuan, China,
are famous for their lofty crags
and jagged peaks.
It is said that elves and spirits live here.
There are many legends in these parts.
One of these are about immortals
possessing supernatural powers.
They fly on their swords, chase the wind
and the stars.
They tune their minds and bodies
in search of the eternal truths of the universe,
so that Man and Nature can be one.
Remember, Omei students,
never succumb to greed and jealousy.
That's the beginning of all evil.
During my recent training,
I could feel a strong force working against us.
I could hear cries of horror which filled me
with a sense of foreboding.
The evil forces could be
attempting another assault
Omei being the leading school in these mountains,
we must be prepared
for a surprise attack.
We safeguard peace and order in the Zu mountains
Look at the aura over Omei.
They have a great following,
unlike us,
there's only you and me here.
The tradition in Kun Lun is based on yin and yang.
The sun and moon represent Kun Lun,
hence there's only been one teacher one student.
King Sky, how long have you studied with me?
200 years.
200 years... How time flies.
Yet I haven't been able to change.
I still miss my teacher
after all these years.
I'm still affected by emotions,
that's why my training cannot progress.
I don't want you to end up like me.
You have to leave me.
This is my weapon the Moon Orb.
Don't come back until you've mastered it.
If I'm not here when you come back,
the Moon Orb will find me.
It'll bring you to me.
The Sun and Moon Orbs are
the protectors of Kun Lun
if the evil force invades...
what will you do?
My destiny depends on your success. Go now!
I'll worry about that when it happens.
200 years later
500 years ago, Insomnia destroyed the Wah Shan Clan.
300 years after that,
the Kun Lun.
And now, he's targeting Omei.
The battle between good and evil is eternal.
But Insomnia is moving sooner than we expected
We must evacuate all innocent humans nearby.
Right now, two armies are at war nearby.
Insomnia means business,
there will be a major conflict
Go and evacuate the armies now,
get them as far away from here as possible.
Yes, sir, at once.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Red, it's been a long time.
King Sky, you've beaten me to it.
ln your clan.
everything must go through the system
One can never act without instructions.
Frankly. l'm surprised you're here at all.
If Insomnia hadn't
destroyed Kun Lun 200 years ago,
you'd probably be in the same position.
Anyway, a war is inevitable.
How would you judge Insomnia's strength?
Omei is the last line of defense.
As lnsomnia has made a move. he can't be bluffing.
From what l've seen on my way here.
he is many times more powerful than before.
In that case, we must evacuate those troops first.
The path ahead has suddenly changed into a cliff.
There were ghostly cries coming from 3 miles away.
This is just a ploy. They won't scare us off.
We must forge ahead at all costs!
Yes, sir!
Pioneers!
Sir!
Captain Lo and Captain Tai.
Go with my daughter as the advance party.
Sir!
Hurry up, we're moving out!
You saw what happened.
This is beyond your powers.
Remove your heavy armour,
and get as far away from here as you can.
We're soldiers. We're scared of nothing!
Just who do you think you are! Arrest them! Execute them!
Sir!
You have no idea who you're dealing with.
Do you know who that is?
That's Insomnia, an extremely powerful force!
There's no time to argue.
This evil monster is very close now,
by the time you see him you'll all be dead!
You've shown up at last.
You two are nothing!
I'm not interested in fighting with you.
So this is what you look like.
Go on, fight!
You'll never conquer your own demons.
Anyway, you just don't have what it takes,
and nobody can help you with that.
Whitebrows! You're a hypocrite
sending two beginners as cannon fodder.
Your disciples don't know the true face
that's hidden behind that facade of righteousness!
Heaven and Thunder Swords.
7 Saints and 300 Castles
will follow me to fight evil at Conch Valley!
Sir!
The Sky Reflector points to this spot.
lnsomnia must be nearby.
Heaven Strikes!
Thunder Fires!
lt's big brother!
Grand Master!
Who's that?
A friend from Kun Lun. l think.
lnsomnia's over there!
He's up there!
He's trying to suck you in!
What's in there?
lts power overcame both Heaven and Thunder swords
they were almost sucked in.
l believe this must be the Blood Cave
that many great masters have searched for.
l now realize what lnsomnia is up to.
He's used our power
to open the Blood Cave.
lf he's able to obtain the power within.
none of us would be his match.
We were wrong about lnsomnia.
he didn't start an early attack on Omei.
it's only starting now.
Let me go in and kill him!
l'll go!
No. Your two swords are the guardians of Omei.
if you're trapped in there. Omei will be finished.
The 7 of us can go!
lf something does happen to us
it won't put your plans in jeopardy.
We knew once we're in here.
it won't be easy to get out.
l suggest we split up.
Whoever finds lnsomnia waits here.
We're not leaving here until we find him.
lf one of us is possessed by the demon.
we must agree that the other will not hesitate.
He must kill him!
Don't worry. l agree.
Though very old friends are we.
Still we must part.
Keep watch outside the cave.
No matter what happens in there.
don't use weapons.
Just wait here. l'll try to rescue them.
Remember. conserve your power!
The Sky Reflector!
Red! King Sky!
The Sky Reflector ...
lt's been sucked away! What now?
The cave is closing up! Get out of here!
lt's like a maze inside the cave.
how far in do you think it goes?
Since he's gone in there. it probably stretches
all the way to the base of the Zu mountains.
We don't have much time. let's split up.
Red!
Yes. sir.
You have experience of the power in the cave.
and you've had more training than others.
so l want you to guard the entrance.
lf you see anything. inform Omei at once.
lf anyone or anything tries to come out. kill it!
l'm the head student in Omei.
l'll take up the first line of defense!
King Sky. though you're not from Omei.
this is the survival of everyone on the mountains.
Please inform Point Nirvana and all other clans.
tell them to guard their own energyforce
to make sure it doesn't dissipate.
lt's my duty to destroy this monster!
l'll go now.
l didn't think we'd get out alive.
l hope we'll be able to work together again.
We are.
We just split up as we did before.
Come back soon. we need you!
Heaven and Thunder. 7 Saints and others
follow me.
We need to prepare for lnsomnia
when he re-emerges.
Yes!
Big brother. Take care.
Take care.
King Sky has strong feelings towards you.
l've known him for 200 years.
l know there's only one woman for him.
that's his teacher.
But if he has feelings for you.
that means he's changed.
The feelings were only fleeting.
l'm not surprised he could change after 200years.
but we're going to train for thousands of years.
so what does that matter?
Enigma. we're going!
Though the 9 magic flowers in Omei
did not all blossom
the energy here is still very strong.
As soon as your man informed us of the danger.
l immediately had the whole place
protected by sacred scriptures.
Yet that didn't stop the energy draining away.
lt looks like the Blood Cave has begun drawing
our energy through the bottom of the mountain.
l'm worried that even my Golden Dragon Seal
may not be able to avert a disaster.
The magic flowers are withering!
Omei's energy is dissipating!
Our powers will also wither with the flowers.
Good forces are waning.
evil forces are on the rise
To ensure we can defeat lnsomnia
we'll need other weapons
to complement the Heaven and Thunder Swords.
Are Heaven and Thunder powerful enough?
to take care of lnsomnia?
They need to merge to release their ultimate power
Unfortunately they haven't managed that so far.
We must achieve that
before the 8 flowers wither.
Heaven and Thunder are male and female.
They can complement or
be detrimental to each other
The two minds must work as one during the merge.
Even the slightest mistake
can kill you both. in body and spirit.
You and l must think as one.
After 1.000 years. 2.000 years ...
Will we still be able to think as one?
Hollow. look out!
Who's there?
Yes. she's your teacher Dawn of 200 years ago.
l must enter another dimension to find
l've been chief of Omei for 2.000 years.
during which time
our clan has grown and prospered.
Now l must go into meditation
for the coming battle
As Red has to guard the Blood Cave.
King Sky will take over as chief of Omei.
All Omei students must abide
by King Sky's orders.
That is my order.
l must get him to teach me!
l must get him to teach me ...
No one in Omei can use the Thunder Sword anymore.
The only hope
lies in Hollow's spirit in the sword.
l can use that to create another man
but he will no longer be Hollow.
How much of Hollow's power survives
will depend on fate.
You're pretty. but a demon's still a demon!
Killing you is like squashing an ant!
You're nothing. l'd only soil my hands.
Guard the entrance.
lf you see anything. inform Omei at once.
lf anyone or anything tries to come out. kill it!
lf the merge of Heaven and Thunder
is not enough to deal with this disaster.
then we'll need the 3 elements to merge.
What's that?
To have 3 forces combine as one.
They are power of the mind.
power of the universe and power of regeneration
When l'm gone.
the Ming Fire l leave behind will be the mind
the weapon in the other dimension is the universe
as for the power of regeneration ...
Where is that?
That power is within you.
To merge the 3 you must first perceive this power.
People will worry if they know l've left my body
so you mustn't tell anyone.
What if something happens. how do l find you?
You can't.
Just do what you think is right.
and rely on the Ming Fire. the power of my mind.
The fire lives. l live.
lf l find the power of the universe.
you'll see a signal in the sky.
At that time we can launch a full counter-attack.
What if the men want to find you?
The Ming Fire will transmit my image to them.
Our survival depends on
the merge of the 3 elements
l must go now.
Good will triumph over evil!
Good will triumph over evil.
Grand Master.
l can feel the energy warning in Omei.
Has something happened in Omei?
Red. you must have faith in me. l told you ...
l have everything under control.
His time has not yet come.
lnsomnia won't be able to use his magic
So don't worry.
just guard the cave
and don't let him out.
lf anything happens. let me know.
Anyway. you must be strong.
You must never waiver.
Anyway ...
just await my good news.
Hollow!
He's not Hollow.
Whitebrows has given him a new name Ying.
He needs to relearn everything.
You know him well.
it's best you be his teacher.
Ridiculous! Anyone who wants to study in Omei
must first find his own sword.
Only then will he become one of us!
Hollow! l'm Enigma.
we practiced the double sword together. remember?
Hollow!
l'm going to be your teacher. understand?
He has no recollection of the past.
To restore his memory. you have to open his mind.
Once he remembers. his powers will return.
Emotions can be a major obstacle.
Don't let the past inhibit you from teaching him.
You can be my student for now. l'll wait.
Why're you still here?
You can't fly without your wings?
You're useless. what's all your training for?
l'll help you.
Now you have your wings back. fly away!
Though l have wings l can't fly away.
l can give you freedom. l can also take your life!
So behave!
l could kill you with my little finger!
This is my sword!
l've found my sword!
l can speak!
l can speak clearly! Can you hear me?
Can l be your student?
Student?
l can teach you manythings
but l don't believe in this master
and student nonsense.
So will you teach me?
Let's start!
When will l be able to fly like them?
Fly!
You're so ugly.
and you ... can't ... even ... fly!
Forget it!
Think of the past. it may help you to remember.
Think? How can l with a sword like this?
You're the teacher you should know!
Maybe l should be your teacher? Think about that!
How can l make you learn?
Stop pushing me! You've taught me nothing!
Just what do you want from me?
Teach me if you want but don't tie me up!
You were a good fighter.
You and your sword were the guardians of Omei.
You can keep this scrap iron. give me yours!
Find yourself another teacher!
l will!
l'll be the teacher!
l'll open your mind!
l'll open your stupid mind!
l'll open your damn stupid mind!
Why're you fighting me?
Don't you want to be with me anymore?
Do you want to go back to Omei?
lf you go back we'll be separated.
Don't you want me anymore?
Merge of the 3 elements?
To l have 3 forces combine as one.
They are power of the mind.
power of the universe and power of regeneration.
Where's the power of regeneration?
That power is within you
To merge the 3 you must first perceive this power.